Connie Regan-Blake collection, 1974-2014
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Connie Regan-Blake collection, 1974-2014 1974-2014
AFC 2015/003
Regan-Blake, Connie, 1947-
11,879 items; 44 containers; 27 linear feet
1 sound tape reel: analog; 10 in.
8 sound cassettes: analog.
12 sound disc (CD): digital; 4 3/4 in.: analog.
5 videocassettes (U-Matic): sound, color.
5 videocassettes (Beta): sound, color.
53 videocassettes (VHS): sound, color.
1 videodiscs (DVD): digital.
942 photographic prints: black-and-white, color; various sizes.
3231 film negatives: color.
597 film negatives: black-and-white.
111 slides: color.
approximately 6875 items.
38 items.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Papers and audiovisual materials comprising the professional archive of storyteller Connie Regan-Blake created and produced during her career from the 1960s to 2014. Includes video and audio interviews of Connie Regan-Blake; recordings of her performances and those of other storytellers at folk festivals, storytelling festivals, and media events and television programs. Regan-Blake performed at the National Storytelling Festival beginning in the 1970s and for many years as part of the storytelling duo, Folktellers, with her first cousin Barbara Freeman. The collection includes the Folktellers play, Mountain sweet talk, (Asheville, North Carolina's longest running theatrical production). Correspondents include Frank and Anne Warner, David McClosky, Rosa Hicks, English folklorist Katharine Briggs, Ashley Bryan, Kathryn Windham, Joan Bloss (Newberry Award winner), and Jimmy Neil Smith among many others; with photographs, programs; contracts; diaries; and artifacts.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Briggs, Katharine Mary--Correspondence.; Freeman, Barbara, 1944-; Hicks, Ray, 1922-2003.; Raymond, Tom, 1947-; Regan-Blake, Connie, 1947-; Regan-Blake, Connie, 1947- --Interviews.; Regan-Blake, Connie, 1947- --Photographs.; Regan-Blake, Connie, 1947- Mountain sweet talk.; Smith, Jimmy Neil--Correspondence.; Warner, Anne--Correspondence.; Warner, Frank, 1903-1978--Correspondence.
Organizations
Folktellers; Folktellers.; National Storytelling Festival.
Subjects
Children's stories, American.; Fairy tales.; Folk festivals--United States.; Ghost stories.; Storytellers--United States.; Storytelling festivals.; Storytelling--Appalachian Region.; Tales.; Women storytellers--North Carolina--Asheville--Biography.
Places
Appalachian Region--Social life and customs.; Asheville (N.C.)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Correspondence.; Drawings.; Field recordings.; Filmed interviews.; Folk tales.; Interviews (Sound recordings); Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
Acquisition
Connie Regan-Blake; 2015.
Accruals
Further accruals are expected.
Related Material
International Storytelling Collection (AFC 2001/008), Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. Contains correspondence, ephemera, graphic images, sound and moving images of Connie Regan-Blake. https://lccn.loc.gov/2004695174
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Access may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Biographical Note
Storyteller Connie Regan-Blake was a key figure in the 1970s American storytelling revival. She has performed at every one of the National Storytelling Festivals, and is a founding member of what is now the International Storytelling Center. She began her career telling stories in a public library in Chattanooga, Tennessee, and later teamed up with her cousin, Barbara Freeman, to form the storytelling duo, Folktellers, from the mid-1970s through the mid-1990s. They wrote and starred in a two-woman play, Mountain Sweet Talk, the longest running theatrical production in Asheville, North Carolina, with seven seasons and more than 300 performances.
Regan-Blake was born January 20, 1947, in Alabama, raised in Florida, and has been a resident of Asheville for more than 30 years. After earning a Bachelor of Arts degree, in 1969 from Loyola University in New Orleans, she traveled throughout Europe. Upon her return to the U.S., she worked with Freeman at the Chattanooga Public Library as part of the childhood literacy program, M.O.R.E. (Making Our Reading Enjoyable). It was then Regan-Blake earned the nickname, "Miss Daisy."
In 1973, she and her cousin attended the first National Storytelling Festival in Jonesborough, Tennessee, where they formed lifelong friendships with many storytellers, including the founder of the Festival, Jimmy Neil Smith, Doc McConnell, and Ray and Rosa Hicks. The following year, Regan-Blake became a founding board member of the International Storytelling Center, formerly known as the National Association of the Preservation and Perpetuation of Storytelling (NAPPS) and the National Storytelling Association (NSA). She served as the artistic director of the National Storytelling Festival (1978-1983) and as the chairperson of the board of directors (1981-1984).
Regan-Blake has hosted storytelling events, workshops and coaching classes. She is the recipient of numerous awards, including the Oracle Awards Program’s Lifetime Achievement Award, Circle of Excellence Award and the Distinguished National Service Award. She has received the B.B. Maurer West Virginia Folklife Scholar Award and two awards from the North Carolina Arts Council.
Scope and Content
Papers and audiovisual materials comprising the professional archive of storyteller Connie Regan-Blake created and produced during her career from the 1960s to 2014. Includes video and audio interviews of Connie Regan-Blake; recordings of her performances and those of other storytellers at folk festivals, storytelling festivals, and media events and television programs. Regan-Blake performed at the National Storytelling Festival beginning in the 1970s and for many years as part of the storytelling duo, Folktellers, with her first cousin Barbara Freeman. The collection includes the Folktellers play, Mountain Sweet Talk, (Asheville, North Carolina's longest running theatrical production). Correspondents include Frank and Anne Warner, David McClosky, Rosa Hicks, English folklorist Katharine Briggs, Ashley Bryan, Kathryn Windham, Joan Bloss (Newberry Award winner), and Jimmy Neil Smith among many others; with photographs, programs; contracts; diaries; and artifacts.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: 1. Manuscripts; 2. Sound Recordings; 3. Graphic Materials; 4. Moving Images; 5. Artifacts and Ephemera. The manuscripts and graphic images are described at folder level. Emphasis was placed on arranging the materials intellectually rather than chronologically.
Series I: Manuscripts
Series II: Sound Recordings
Series III: Graphic Materials
Series IV: Moving Images
Series V: Artifacts and Ephemera
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscripts ca. 1976-1998
  - Subseries A: The Folktellers, 1971-1999
    - Administrative, 1976-2016, undated (1 of 4) (Box-folder 1/1)
      Press releases, workshop evaluations, travel schedules, and meeting notes pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Administrative, 1976-2007, undated (2 of 4) (Box-folder 1/2)
      Press releases, biographies, invoices, police reports for burglary, fee lists, certificates, itineraries, shareholders agreement, and inventory pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Administrative, 1980-1996, undated (3 of 4) (Box-folder 1/3)
      Contracts, correspondence, statements, and notes pertaining to royalties for The Folktellers.
    - Administrative, 1993-1995, undated (4 of 4) (Box-folder 1/4)
      Correspondence, notes, agreements, and rough drafts pertaining to selling The Folktellers' company.
    - Notes, 1976-1995, undated (Box-folder 1/5)
      Notes by and pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Recommendation letters and thank you letters, 1978-1994 (Box-folder 1/6)
      Recommendation letters from Jimmy Neil Smith, President of NAPPS.
    - Correspondence, 1975-1994 (1 of 4) (Box-folder 1/7)
      The Folktellers' correspondence with libraries, publishers, Chinese schoolchildren, and others.
    - Correspondence, 1982-1995 (2 of 4) (Box-folder 2/1)
      The Folktellers' correspondence with publishers, production companies, radio, and television stations, and NAPPS.
    - Correspondence, 1980-1999 (3 of 4) (Box-folder 2/2)
      The Folktellers' correspondence with libraries, publishers, and Japanese storyteller Shigeo Watanabe.
    - Correspondence, 1980-1995 (4 of 4) (Box-folder 2/3)
      The Folktellers' correspondence with publishers, other storytellers, production companies, radio and television stations, and letters from children.
    - Articles and reviews, 1982-1996 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Articles and reviews, 1971-1993 (2 of 3) (Box-folder 2/5)
    - Articles and reviews, 1977-1988 (3 of 3) (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Contracts, agreements, and permissions, 1977-1998 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 2/7)
      The Folktellers' contracts with publishers, production companies, festivals, radio, and television stations.
    - Contracts, agreements, and permissions, 1980-1997 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 2/8)
      The Folktellers' contracts with NAPPS, 700 Club, TBS, production companies, radio and television stations, and other storytellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1993, undated (1 of 13) (Box-folder 3/1)
      Newsletters and press releases pertaining to The Folktellers. One poster advertising the movie, Winter People is in oversize box 44.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1990, undated (2 of 13) (Box-folder 3/2)
      Newsletters, flyers, and order forms pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1982, undated (3 of 13) (Box-folder 3/3)
      Flyers pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1982, undated (4 of 13) (Box-folder 3/4)
      Flyers and advertisements pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1975-1988 (5 of 13) (Box-folder 3/5)
      Calendars and schedules pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1978-1985, undated (6 of 13) (Box-folder 3/6)
      Posters pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1989, undated (7 of 13) (Box-folder 3/7)
      Brochures and programs pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1977-1981, undated (8 of 13) (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1990 (9 of 13) (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1980, undated (10 of 13) (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Promotional materials, 1975-1990 (11 of 13) (Box-folder 4/4)
      Programs pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-2006, undated (12 of 13) (Box-folder 4/5)
      Programs, postcards, artwork, and mini-guides pertaining to The Folktellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-1995, undated (13 of 13) (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Subseries B: Children's drawings ca. 1997, undated
    - Children's drawings, (1 of 5) (Box 44)
    - Children's drawings, (2 of 5) (Box 44)
    - Children's drawings, (3 of 5) (Box 44)
    - Children's drawings, (4 of 5) (Box 44)
    - Children's drawings, (5 of 5) (Box 44)
  - Subseries C: Mountain sweet talk, 1985-1992
    - Script, 1989 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 5/1)
      Typed script for Mountain sweet talk.
    - Script, 1991-1992 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 5/2)
      Script for Christmas version of Mountain sweet talk.
    - Legal documentation, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 5/3)
      Contracts, permission forms, and copyright information pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Production materials, 1986 (1 of 3) (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Production materials, 1987-1990, undated (2 of 3) (Box-folder 5/5)
      Production notes, revised script (1989), programs, and schedules pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Production materials, 1986, undated (3 of 3) (Box-folder 6/1)
      Notes for the sound technician and the proposed budget for Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, 1983-1993 (1 of 8) (Box-folder 6/2)
      Brochures, programs, and newspaper articles pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, 1989-1992 (2 of 8) (Box-folder 6/3)
      Brochures, programs, flyers, and newspaper articles pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, 1986-1988, undated (3 of 8) (Box-folder 6/4)
      Programs and articles pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, 1988-1989, undated (4 of 8) (Box-folder 6/5)
      Programs, brochures, articles, and notes pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, 1986-1993, undated (5 of 8) (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Promotional materials, 1986-1989, undated (6 of 8) (Box-folder 6/7)
      Brochures, advertisements, and articles pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, 1986-1992, undated (7 of 8) (Box-folder 6/8)
      Brochures, advertisements, flyers, and articles pertaining to Mountain sweet talk.
    - Promotional materials, undated (8 of 8) (Box-folder 6/9)
      Photocopies of images and logos used for advertising and creating album covers.
  - Subseries D: Connie Regan-Blake's solo career, 1991-2015
    - Administrative, 1997-2014, undated (1 of 5) (Box-folder 7/1)
      Biographies, contact lists, agreements, invoices, and order forms pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Administrative, 1996-2014, undated (2 of 5) (Box-folder 7/2)
      Invoices, articles, website printouts, and registration forms pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Administrative, 1998-2015 (3 of 5) (Box-folder 7/3)
      Registration forms pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Administrative, 1992-1999 (4 of 5) (Box-folder 7/4)
      Workshop records pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Administrative, 1995-2000 (5 of 5) (Box-folder 7/5)
      Evaluations pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Correspondence, 1995-2014 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Recommendation letters, thank you letters, and letters from children, 1996-2007 (Box-folder 7/7)
      Letters from fans, including a recommendation letter from Jimmy Neil Smith, President of NAPPS.
    - Notes, 1995-2015, undated (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Promotional materials, 1998-2016, undated (1 of 5) (Box-folder 8/2)
      Flyers pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Promotional materials, 1985-2013, undated (2 of 5) (Box-folder 8/3)
      Flyers pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake's events.
    - Promotional materials, 1997-2015, undated (3 of 5) (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Promotional materials, 1996-2015, undated (4 of 5) (Box-folder 8/5)
      Brochures, artwork, awards, and certificates pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Promotional materials, 2003-2015 (5 of 5) (Box-folder 8/6)
      Brochures, artwork, and programs pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Bead for Life, 2006-2014 (Box-folder 8/7)
      Articles, notes, and flyers for Bead for Life.
    - Tell It In the Mountains Festival, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 8/8)
      Brochures, documentation, correspondence, and notes for Tell It In the Mountains Festival. Connie Regan-Blake was the festival's artistic director for seven years.
  - Subseries E: Contracts, 1981-2014
    Storytelling contracts, notes and other documents for Connie Regan-Blake's solo career separated by state.
    - Contracts, 1995-2011 (1 of 17) (Box-folder 9/1)
      Contracts for Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas, and California events.
    - Contracts, 1995-2000 (2 of 17) (Box-folder 9/2)
      Contracts for Colorado and Connecticut events.
    - Contracts, 1994-2011 (3 of 17) (Box-folder 9/3)
      Contracts for Florida events.
    - Contracts 1991-2012 (4 of 17) (Box-folder 9/4)
      Contracts for Florida and Georgia events.
    - Contracts, 1996-2009 (5 of 17) (Box-folder 10/1)
      Contracts for Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, and Louisiana events.
    - Contracts, 1984-2007 (6 of 17) (Box-folder 10/2)
      Contracts for Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, and Minnesota events.
    - Contracts, 1994-2008 (7 of 17) (Box-folder 10/3)
      Contracts for Mississippi, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, and New York events.
    - Contracts, 1993-2013 (8 of 17) (Box-folder 10/4)
      Contracts for North Carolina events.
    - Contracts, 1998-2005 (9 of 17) (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Contracts, 1994-2011 (10 of 17) (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Contracts, 1991-2014 (11 of 17) (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Contracts, 1981-2012 (12 of 17) (Box-folder 11/4)
      Contracts for Ohio, Oklahoma, and Pennsylvania events.
    - Contracts, 1997-2009 (13 of 17) (Box-folder 12/1)
      Contracts for Texas, Utah, and Vermont events.
    - Contracts, 1994-2010 (14 of 17) (Box-folder 12/2)
      Contracts for Tennessee events.
    - Contracts, 1996-2010 (15 of 17) (Box-folder 12/3)
      Contracts for Rhode Island and South Carolina events.
    - Contracts, 1989-2011 (16/17) (Box-folder 12/4)
      Contracts for Virginia events.
    - Contracts, 1987-2009 (17 of 17) (Box-folder 12/5)
      Contracts for Virginia, West Virginia, Wisconsin, and Wyoming events.
    - Documentation for North Carolina Symphony performances, 2012 (Box-folder 12/6)
      Contracts, correspondence, notes, flyers, itinerary, and script for performances with the North Carolina Symphony.
    - Documentation for New Zealand performances, 1996-2012, undated (Box-folder 12/7)
      Brochures, itineraries, contracts, notes, and tickets for the New Zealand performances.
    - Blank performance and schedule forms, undated (Box-folder 12/8)
      A list of items needed for performing, including a to-do list. Also includes blank itinerary, income, and booking forms.
  - Subseries F: Ledgers, 1984-2000
    - Accounting ledger, 1984-1985 (1 of 3) (Box 44)
    - Accounting ledger, 1995-1998 (2 of 3) (Box 44)
    - Accounting ledger, 1995-2000 (3 of 3) (Box 44)
  - Subseries G: Other storytellers, 1975-2014
    - Administrative, 1981-2014 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 13/1)
      Directories, playbill, postcards, and press release pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Administrative, 1997, undated (2 of 2) (Box-folder 13/2)
      Writings and artwork pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Biographies, 2003-2007, undated (1 of 2) (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Biographies, 1984-2008, undated (2 of 2) (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Promotional materials, 1976-2011, undated (1 of 7) (Box-folder 13/5)
      Programs and brochures pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1976-2016, undated (2 of 7) (Box-folder 13/6)
      Brochures pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1995-2015, undated (3 of 7) (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Promotional materials, 1975-2000, undated (4 of 7) (Box-folder 14/1)
      Flyers pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1975-2000, undated (5 of 7) (Box-folder 14/2)
      Order forms, calendars, and newsletters pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1977-2008, undated (6 of 7) (Box-folder 14/3)
      Newsletters pertaining to other storytellers.
    - Promotional materials, 1987-2004 (7 of 7) (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Articles and reviews, 1975-2006, undated (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Promotional materials for Dorothy Kirk, 2012-2015 (Box-folder 14/6)
      Brochures and flyers for Dorothy Kirk's shows. Kirk is a former student of Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Ray and Rosa Hicks, 1977-2014 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 14/7)
      Flyers, correspondence, notes, and articles pertaining to the Hicks family and Connie Regan-Blake.
    - Ray and Rosa Hicks, 1977-2014 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 14/8)
    - NAPPS/National Storytelling Center, 1984-2011, undated (Box-folder 14/9)
      Brochures, flyers, and articles pertaining to The International Storytelling Center. Also includes an article by Jimmy Neil Smith on the origins of the National Storytelling Festival.
  - Subseries H: Business cards
    - Business cards (1 of 3) (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Business cards (2 of 3) (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Business cards (3 of 3) (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Subseries I: Magazines, 1978-2014
    Articles in magazines pertaining to Connie Regan-Blake and The Folktellers.
    - Magazines, 1978-2014 (Box-folder 18/1)
      The Laurel of Asheville (July 2014), National Storytelling Journal (Winter 1986), Laugh Makers (1994), Washington Flyer (September/October 1989), and the School Library Journal (November 1978).
    - Magazines, 1978-2014 (Box-folder 18/2)
      Republic Scene (September 1981), Quest (November/December 1979), Mother Earth News (November/December 1978), and Celebrate Story! (2014).
    - Magazines, 1981-2013 (Box-folder 18/3)
      Our State (November 2006), American Way (September 1982), Country Journal (October 1981), WNC Magazine (September 2011), and LaGrange Life (March 2013).
    - Magazines, 1978-2011 (Box-folder 18/4)
      New Age (July 1980), School Library Journal (January 1989), Carolina Mountain Life (Summer 2011), Southern Outdoors (October 1978), and Tennessee Magazine (September 1978).
    - Magazines, 1976-2012 (Box-folder 18/5)
      Southern Living (October 1976), WNC Woman (August 2010, March 2012-April 2012, and July 2014).
    - Magazines, 1988-2014 (Box-folder 19/1)
      Smithsonian (March 1997), Storytelling Magazine (January 1997), Lady's Circle (June 1988), Goldenseal (Summer 1997), WNC Magazine (September 2011), Laurel of Asheville (July 2014), and Blue Ridge (October 1996).
    - Magazines, 1978-2009 (Box-folder 19/2)
      Southern Outdoors (October 1978), Kalliope article (Undated), Jacksonville Public Libraries Annual Report (1985-86), Laurel of Asheville (July 2008), Loyola (Summer 2007), Journal of the Tar Hell Tellers (September 2009), and Good Housekeeping (September 1984).
    - Magazines, 1991-2006 (Box-folder 19/3)
      Mountain Traditions (Fall 2006), Inside Arts (Fall 1994), Kalliope (1991), Library Journal (July 1996), Sing Out! (November/December 1996 January 1997), and Sing Out! (February-April 1996).
    - Magazines, 1982-2011 (Box-folder 19/4)
      National Geographic (November 1982), The State (September 1988), Washington Flyer (September/October 1989), Blue Ridge Parkway Directory (1990-91), Storytelling Magazine (January/February 2011), North Carolina Humanities Newsletter (Spring 2003), Loyola of the South (Fall 1988), and Traditions (2010-2011).
    - Magazines, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 20/1)
      National Geographic (January 1991), Good Housekeeping (April 1987), and Southern Living (October 1986).
    - Magazines, 1983-2010 (Box-folder 20/2)
      WNC Magazine (September/October 2007), Folklife Center News (Winter/Spring 2010), National Storytelling Journal (Winter 1988), and Mother Earth News (January/February 1983).
    - Magazines, 1982-2014 (Box-folder 20/3)
      School Library Journal (October 1982), GEO (August 1983), Southern Living (September 1983), and Storytelling Magazine (April/May 2014).
  - Subseries J: Newspapers, 1971-2015
    Newspaper articles and clippings documenting Connie Regan Blake's career.
    - Newspapers, 2008-2013 (Box-folder 21/1)
      Johnson City Press (May 2013), Post & Courier (May 2008), Asheville Citizen-Times (June 2013, December 2012), and Mountain Xpress (December 2013).
    - Newspapers, 1974-2013 (Box-folder 21/2-3)
      Savannah Morning News (January 1995), Chattanooga Times (October 1974), Asheville Citizen-Times (June 2013, April 2004, February 2005, May 2004), Novedades de Yucatan (March 1983), and Mountain Xpress (March 2013).
    - Newspapers, 1979-2015 (Box-folder 21/4-5)